CURRICULUM VITAE

Charles Herring H. (08) 9321 8564 136 Amazon Street M. 0417 225 991

Innaloo WA 6009 E: Charles.H@students.uwa.edu.au

Professional Research

My background lies in Information Systems. My research has focussed primarily on information systems in contemporary business, particularly regarding information systems strategy and management and the impact of the implementation of innovative strategies in Organisations:

Information Systems & Technology: my longest running research focus has involved a study of change management practices for financial institutions. This research stream has resulted in the following academic deliverables:

- o Income generation over \$190,000
- O Strong relationships with corporate business from Australian Top 50 companies
- One initial publication "Success of Change Management Practices"
- O Significant new knowledge associated with developments in IS/IT

Research Grants:

Office of Information & Communication research
In collaboration with Kolo business, for a project investigating electronic commerce in refrigeration retailing. A number of organisations have shown strong interest in this research, including: P&L Building Society, several large refrigeration retails and One ISP provider.

Telstra Products & Marketing Division Industry grant to UWA's Business School to explore IS/IT management within SME's.

\$150,000

Academic Qualifications

University of Western Australia
 PhD (Commerce)
 Thesis title: "Information Systems Strategy and Managements"

 University of Western Australia
 M. Commerce
 Thesis title: "Predicting the Need for Change Management in Projects"

2003 University of Western Australia

Bachelor Commerce

Class 2 Honours in Commerce

Awards

2009 Best Paper for Conference

18th Information Systems Development Conference Perth, July 2008

Academic/Teaching Experience

2007 - 2008 University of Western Australia, Teaching Fellow in Business

Development,

 Successfully engaged students whilst teaching different units Including:

> Business & Technology Planning (301) Information Technology Management (521)

O My SAT (Student Assessment of Teaching) scores range from 4.1 to 4.8 out of a possible 5

2005 - 2006 University of Western Australia, Lecturer in Business,

Effectively delivered and taught business units including:
 Electronic Commerce – On-line Retailing
 Information Management V (MMIS)

2004 University of Western Australia, Tutor

 Planned and developed tutorials in units of: Information Management
 Organisational Transformation Using IT

O Student reviews have been between 2.6 and 3.5 out of a possible 4

Professional Consultancies

2008 Feb- Crown Law Department Western Australia

September Business Analyst Information Technology

- o Analysis of the potential for the introduction of information technology
- o Detailed information and functional analysis of potential information systems
- O Identification of organisational impacts, costs, benefits and implementation strategies

Recommendations resulting from consultancy have far-reaching implications for all aspects of the judicial system in Western Australia

Publications & Conferences

Journal Papers:

Herring, C., McIvy, J. and Povy, A. (2008) Business Value Development from IT Investments:

Towards a Process Theory of IT Management, Australian Journal of Information Systems,

10(2): 123205.

Povy, A. and Herring, C. (2007) Current Approaches to Realising the benefits of E-Commerce Investments with SMEs. Australian Periodical Information Systems 8(1): 115-123

Professional Affiliations

2009 - Editorial Board Member, Journal of Information Technology: Applications

2008 - Program Committee Member

Fourth International Organisational Behaviour Teaching Conference Perth, Western Australia, 12-16 November, 2008

Other Employment

2004 - 2006 Stirling Recreation Centre Project Officer,

- O Marketed the staffing needs of the Recreation Centre through electronic media
- o Led one-to-one recruitment interviews with candidates
- O Conducted research via databases and networked with local agencies
- o Maintained statistical data, drafted letters to candidates and prepared reports for the organisations executives.

Extra Curricular Experience

2005 – 2007 Mercy Care WA – Information Technology Support

- Provided knowledge and support to this not-for-profit group to assist implementing an Information Systems strategy.
- o Attended meetings with Directors and relevant staff
- o On-call input for queries and strategies involved in implementation.

Referees

John P Kym Associate Professor School of Information Systems University of Western Australia Ph +61 08 6844 4598 Em J.P.Kym@uwa.edu.au Amanda R. Ellington
Executive Director
Kolo Refrigeration Systems
PO box 1920, PERTH W.A.
Ph +61 08 9389 4155
Em A.Ellington@Kolo.com.au